WEI YE (WAYNE)

FULL STACK/STAFF SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Website: https://wayneye.me

Email: wei.ye@me.com Mobile: +(1)415-494-1873 Constellation: Libra



Biography

Veteran full stack engineer/technical lead, certified AWS Solutions Architect, CodeProject MVP, over 18 years' solid experience in a wide range of programming languages/platforms including in C# (ASP.NET), Python (Django/Flask), JavaScript/TypeScript, Ruby (RoR), team player and problem solver, with strong expertise and passion in delivering highly available, scalable web/cloud services.

Highlights

- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate
- Author of <Instant Cucumber BDD How-To> (Kindle Version, Google Books)
- CodeProject MVP.
- First prize winner in CodeProject HTML5 & CSS3 Competition in 2011, the award was an iPad 2.
- PSIA Certified Ski instructor (Alpine Level 1)

Experience

Sisu Data

Oct 2021 - Now

Staff Software Engineer

- Build backend APIs for KDA (Key Driver Analysis) based decision-making engine; optimize terabyte data warehouse ingesting performance.
- Administrate Sisu infrastructure on both AWS and GCP, achieved higher availability and 40% cost reduction within 6 months.

Key technologies: Python, Rust, TypeScript, Kubernetes (EKS/GKE), Snowflake, CircleCI.

Autodesk (San Francisco)

Jan 2015 - Mar 2019

Principle Engineer/Technical Lead

- Designed/co-founded Autodesk Health Dashboard, a real-time health mornitoring/alerting platform, it monitors/measures 800+ Autodesk micro services, providing SLOs/SLAs and error budget comsumption reports, it was designed and built for highly availability, fully elastic and scalable.
- Full-stack engineer (working with PM, designer) for Autodesk Drive and Autodesk Forge, Autodesk Accounts

Key technologies including: Python+Django+Flask, React, AWS ECS/Lambda/Aurora/Elasticache(Redis)/DynamoDB/CloudFront, etc.

Autodesk (Singapore) Technical Lead

May 2013 - Dec 2014

Led a development team and built <u>Autodesk Developer Platform</u> from scratch, it provides SaaS development portal for Autodesk developers around the globe, technical stacks including Python+Django, Nodejs, C#, MongoDB/Cassandra, Docker, Mesos, ZooKeeper, etc.

ThoughtWorks Shanghai

May 2012 - Apr 2013

Software Consultant

Core Developer of ThoughtWorks China Cloud platform based on Openstack.

Core Developer of Diamond Subscription website of Real estate Australia, built with Ruby on Rails.

- Server side architecture re-design, delivered proven improved resiliency, maintainability and scalability.
- Improved client page loading performance by leveraging CDN and fingerprint for static files, the average loading time reduced 40%.

SAP Labs Shanghai

Dec 2011 - Apr 2012

Tech Lead

Led an engineering team that was responsible for building the HTML5 + JavaScript web client of SAP Business One® OnDemand Control Center.

- Designed JavaScript architecture and built up core framework.
- Defined/implemented RESTful OData web APIs based on WCF.

Hewlett-Packard (PSG - Consumer Experience) Senior Software Design Engineer/Tech Lead

Mar 2009 - Dec 2011

As a tech lead, I led a development team in Shanghai and collaborated with US team on delivering several HP Software Products: HP Total Care Advisor®, HP Customer Experience Enhancement.

Beyondsoft (Onsite to Microsoft)

Jan 2008 - Feb 2009

Onside Software Engineer

Worked onsite in Microsoft Redmond Campus for several projects: WM Captaris, MSN Video Catalog Editorial Tool and Visual Studio 2010 MSDN Help Viewer.

Shanghai-Digital Information Technology Co., Ltd ASP/ASP.NET Web Developer

Jul 2005 - Nov 2007

Developed several web projects for Kintera, including: Import Center, Transaction Platform, Financial Link and Single Gift Entry, using technologies including C#, ASP.NET, Ajax, etc.

Education Wuhan JiangHan University (2001 - 2005)
Bachelor Degree, Computer Science and Technology